Preliminary Inventory of the Terence White Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Terence White collection,
1992-2002
2002C71
White, Terence, collector
10 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize boxes, 1 cubic foot box, 4 oversize folders (6.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Printed matter and miscellany, relating to political and social conditions in Afghanistan and Pakistan.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Photo journalist.
Scope and Content Note
Printed matter and miscellany, relating to political and social conditions in Afghanistan and Pakistan.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Pakistan.; Afghanistan.
Container List
- Printed matter, 1984-2002 (Box 1)
  - Official forms. Visa forms, from the period of Taliban rule in Afghanistan, and "CJTF-Mountain Ground Rules Agreement," press regulations promulgated by United States military forces in Afghanistan, 2002 March 15 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Monographs
    - Mathematics textbook, Afghanistan. (Folder 1: 2)
      In Pushto
    - The Phoenix of Pameer: A Summary of Biography of the Great National Hero the Ever-Lasting Martyr, Ahmad Shah Masoud, n.d. (Folder 1: 3)
      In English
    - Hitler, Adolf, Mein Kampf, Afghanistan. (Folder 1: 4)
    - Koran, Institute of Regional Studies, Afghanistan, 1984. (Folder 1: 5)
      In Russian
    - Basic English Book 1, Islamic Government of Afghanistan, 1992. (Folder 1: 6)
      In English, with some definitions in Pushto
    - Basic English Book 4, Islamic Government of Afghanistan, 1992. (Folder 1: 7)
  - Serial issues., See also Oversize materials, box 3 (Box 2)
    - Andisha-e-Naw. (Folder 2: 1)
      One issue, in Pushto
    - AWA Monthly, no. 3, 2002 March 21. (Folder 2: 2)
      In English and Pushto
    - ISAF News, no. 3. (Folder 2: 3)
    - The Kabul Times, nos. 1-2, 2002 March 26-April 3. (Folder 2: 4)
    - Kabul Weekly, nos. 3,7,9,10,11, 2002 February 7-April 11. (Folder 2: 5)
    - Newsline, 2002 February. (Folder 2: 6)
      Pakistani monthly, in English. Contains coverage of the kidnapping of Daniel Pearl
    - Miscellany. (Folder 2: 7)
      Seven serial issues, in Pushto
  - Postcards. (Folder 2: 8)
    One postcard depicting a young Afghan woman, three postcards depicting romantic scenes, and thirteen postcards depicting Osama bin Laden
  - Miscellany. (Folder 2: 9)
    Photocopies of a Sudanese passport and other materials in the name of El Fatih Ibrahim, a presumed member of Al-Qaeda
- Oversize materials, 2002 (Box 3)
  - One banner promoting literacy, produced for the Ministry of Education of Afghanistan, and with the name and insignia of the United States Agency for International Development. (Folder 3: 1)
  - Two handmade banners from Afghanistan, possibly used by Taliban supporters, with the Islamic inscription, "There is no God but Allah, and Mohammed is His Messenger." (Folder 3: 2)
    In Arabic
  - Three issues of the Weekly Akhbar-E-Jehan, 2002 October 8-28. (Folder 3: 3)
    Published in Karachi, Pakistan
  - One 2002-2003 calendar, produced by the Harakat-e Islami Afghanistan Committee of Cultural (sic). (Folder 3: 4)
    In Pushto and English. Includes some pictures depicting Osama bin Laden
  - One paper flag of Afghanistan, and three small posters from Afghanistan, including one for Ariana Afghan Air Lines (Folder 3: 5)
- One folder containing three posters produced by the Revolutionary Association of the Women of Afghanistan, n.d. (Map-case Map case)
- One folder containing fourteen political and educational posters from Afghanistan, including three depicting Abdul Haq, n.d.
- One folder containing thirty two posters depicting Osama bin Laden, produced in Pakistan after 2001 September 11
- One folder containing two maps of Kabul and one map of a minefield in Afghanistan, 2002
- Incremental Materials (Box 4-12)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.